<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <channel><title>Elting Lab Research - news</title> <description>Science updates from the Elting Lab at NCSU</description><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu</link> <atom:link href="http://physics.ncsu.edu/feed.category.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/> <item><title>Open positions!</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;The Elting Lab has several currently open positions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are recruiting NCSU undergraduates for positions beginning in the Summer of 2022 (with the potential to continue into the school year). For full consideration for these paid positions, interested students should contact Dr. Elting by April 18. See instructions on the Join tab.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are also recruiting one or more postdoctoral scholars to work on the mechanics of the mitotic spindle. Applicants should apply by April 18 to ensure full consideration, though applications will continue to be accepted until the position is filled. See more details on the Join tab.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/OpenPositions/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/OpenPositions/</guid> </item> <item><title>Mohamed and Kim's paper is published!</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;Mohamed and Kim&amp;#39;s paper on mechanical perturbation of the cytokinetic ring by laser ablation, which is a collaboration of our group with the Laplante group (also in the QCDB cluster at NCSU) is now published. See the publications tab for more info!&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/CytokineticRingPaper/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/CytokineticRingPaper/</guid> </item> <item><title>Marc, Parsa, and Ana Sofia's papers are published!</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;Several papers from the group were recently accepted, including Ana Sofia&amp;#39;s first author paper at the Journal of Microscopy (with contributions from lab member Parsa, too, and collaboration with Lex Kemper and Jamie Jennings), Marc&amp;#39;s first author paper at Molecular Biology of the Cell (with contributions from lab members Grant and Elizabeth, and a collaboration with the Ohi group), and two first author papers from Parsa! Check them out on the publications tab.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/New-Papers/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/New-Papers/</guid> </item> <item><title>Parsa's S. pombe spindle ablation preprint selected for a preLight</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;Leeba Ann Chacko selected Parsa&amp;#39;s preprint (&lt;a href="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.10.20.347922"&gt;posted on bioRxiv&lt;/a&gt;) to highlight with a &lt;a href="https://prelights.biologists.com/highlights/the-collapse-of-the-spindle-following-ablation-in-s-pombe-is-mediated-by-microtubules-and-the-motor-protein-dynein/"&gt;preLight post&lt;/a&gt;. We really appreciate the feedback from Leeba, who raises some great questions that we hope to investigate in future work. We also appreciated the chance to respond to some of her questions, and you can read our response at the bottom of the preLight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Side note that in addition to her science, Leeba also makes some amazing science art, which you can check out on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LeebaAnnChacko"&gt;her twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Look at this adorable pombe (with bonus points for the pun): &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I’ve been missing my Pombe buddies since it’s been some time since I’ve been to the lab. Here’s fission (heading) east. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Pombeart?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Pombeart&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SorryNotSorry?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#SorryNotSorry&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/Ix8n1sdWoH"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Ix8n1sdWoH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Leeba Ann Chacko (@LeebaAnnChacko) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LeebaAnnChacko/status/1409340228775464963?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 28, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/Zareiesfandabadi-preLight/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/Zareiesfandabadi-preLight/</guid> </item> <item><title>Preprint of Parsa's S. pombe spindle ablation paper on BioRxiv!</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve posted a new preprint from undergraduate and now post-bac researcher &lt;a href="/eltinglab/team/parsa-zareiesfandabdi/"&gt;Parsa Zareiesfandabadi&lt;/a&gt;. Parsa has interrogated the collapse of the &lt;em&gt;S. pombe&lt;/em&gt; spindle that follows laser ablation. Contrary to previous hypotheses, which implicated the nuclear envelope and/or chromosomes in this motion, Parsa found that it&amp;#39;s microtubule dependent and that the molecular motor dynein is involved. You can read the paper &lt;a href="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.10.20.347922"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/Zareiesfandabadi-Preprint/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/Zareiesfandabadi-Preprint/</guid> </item> <item><title>Preprint of Ana Sofía's spindle tracker paper on BioRxiv!</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;Undergraduate researcher &lt;a href="/eltinglab/team/ana-sofia-uzsoy/"&gt;Ana Sofía Uzsoy&lt;/a&gt; developed a tool to automatically track the two ends of the elongating &lt;em&gt;S. pombe&lt;/em&gt; spindle. You can read the paper &lt;a href="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.10.09.333765v1"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to try out the code, it&amp;#39;s available &lt;ahref="https://github.com/eltinglab/SpindleLengthPlugin"&gt;on Github&lt;/a&gt; as a plug-in for ImageJ. Let us know if you give it a try!&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/Uzsoy-Preprint/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/Uzsoy-Preprint/</guid> </item> <item><title>Elting Lab receives NIH R35 MIRA Grant</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;The Elting Lab has received a five year, R35 Maximizing Investigators&amp;#39; Research Award (MIRA) grant from the National Institute of General Medical Sciences at the NIH. This grant will support our research on the mitotic spindle. We&amp;#39;re very grateful to the NIH for the support, and are excited for the new science this will allow us to do. You can read more about the grant &lt;a href="https://physics.sciences.ncsu.edu/2020/08/18/nc-state-physicist-awarded-1-8-million-for-research-on-cell-division/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Also - we&amp;#39;ll soon be hiring a postdoctoral researcher for this grant! So, if you&amp;#39;re interested in the biophysics of the mitotic spindle and are searching for a postdoc opportunity, watch this space. More information coming soon.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/NIH-MIRA-grant/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/NIH-MIRA-grant/</guid> </item> <item><title>Preprint of Marc's k-fiber bundle paper on BioRxiv!</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;The Elting Lab&amp;#39;s first preprint was posted on BioRxiv! You can read the paper &lt;a href="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.05.19.104661v2"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This project was a great team effort, led by graduate student &lt;a href="/eltinglab/team/marc-begley/"&gt;Marc Begley&lt;/a&gt;, and also including contributions from undergraduates &lt;a href="/eltinglab/team/elizabeth-davis/"&gt;Elizabeth Davis&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="/eltinglab/team/grant-sherrill/"&gt;Grant Sherrill&lt;/a&gt;. Marc et al. ablated bundles of spindle microtubules called k-fibers that are responsible for attaching chromosomes to the mitotic spindle and ultimately for segregating them. This allows us to probe k-fiber mechanical cohesion and its molecular origin. In collaboration with Puck Ohi&amp;#39;s group, we found that the kinesin-12 Kif15 is at least partially responsible for mechanically reinforcing k-fibers.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/Begley-Preprint/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/Begley-Preprint/</guid> </item> <item><title>New lab members!</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve had a bunch of new lab members join since our last update! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, Grant Sherrill joined the Elting Lab last summer. An NCSU undergraduate physics major, he&amp;#39;s working on a project to examine force in S. pombe mitotic spindles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="col-md-5"&gt;&lt;div class="media"&gt; &lt;img width=400 class="media-object" src="/eltinglab/images/news/funfact.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; Rae Fulkerson also joined the lab in the summer as a research technician. Since then, she&amp;#39;s been working on various molecular biology projects, dramatically increasing our overall organization, and regaling us with fun science facts of the week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, Sophia Webster joined the group last fall. She&amp;#39;s bravely agreed to do a joint postdoc with 4 PIs (in addition to Mary, the project is mentored by Julio Belmonte, Caroline Laplante, and Greg Reeves), connected to the Quantitative and Computational Developmental Biology cluster at NCSU. Her project involves examining how mechanics help pattern the developing Drosophila embryo.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/more-new-lab-members/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/more-new-lab-members/</guid> </item> <item><title>Elting lab received collaborative grant from NSF!</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re very excited to announce our lab&amp;#39;s first federal funding, from the National Science Foundation! This grant is an interdisciplinary, collaborative research intiative whose goal is to build synthetic cytoskeletons inside living cells. This project is a multidisciplinary program involving physicists, engineers, cellular biologists, theorists/modelers, and social scientists. In addition to the Elting Lab, we will be collaborating with the groups of &lt;a href="https://www.bhamla.gatech.edu/"&gt;Saad Bhamla&lt;/a&gt; (Georgia Tech), &lt;a href="https://www.fredchanglab.ucsf.edu/"&gt;Fred Chang&lt;/a&gt; (UCSF), &lt;a href="https://sols.asu.edu/jane-maienschein"&gt;Jane Maienschein&lt;/a&gt; (Arizona State University) and &lt;a href="http://dinner-group.uchicago.edu/"&gt;Aaron Dinner&lt;/a&gt; (University of Chicago). You can read more about the award &lt;a href="https://sciences.ncsu.edu/news/team-led-by-nc-state-biophysicist-awarded-1-2-million-to-develop-cyborg-cells/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;#39;re also currently recruiting a postdoc and/or graduate students for this position. Find out more on the &lt;a href="https://physics.ncsu.edu/eltinglab/page/join/"&gt;join page&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/CYBORG-cell-grant/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/CYBORG-cell-grant/</guid> </item> <item><title>Ana Sofia Wins Goldwater Scholarship!</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;Congrats to Elting lab undergraduate Ana Sofia for winning a Goldwater Scholarship! Ana Sofia has engaged in research both in the Elting lab and with an REU at the University of Chicago. See this &lt;a href="https://sciences.ncsu.edu/news/goldwater-scholar-ana-sofia-uzsoy-intelligent-life/"&gt;great profile of Ana Sofia&lt;/a&gt; for more info about her work.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/ana-sofia-goldwater/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/ana-sofia-goldwater/</guid> </item> <item><title>Parsa Wins 3rd Place in NCSU Physics McCormick Symposium</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;All three undergraduate in the Elting Lab - Elizabeth Davis, Ana Sofia Uzsoy, and Parsa Zareiesfandabadi - presented posters in the McCormick Symposium, which showcases undergraduate research in the Physics department at NCSU. A special congratulations to Parsa, whose poster won 3rd place!&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/mccormick-symposium/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/mccormick-symposium/</guid> </item> <item><title>Parsa Recieves Summer Funding from the Office of Undergraduate Research</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Parsa for receiving a grant from the &lt;a href="https://undergradresearch.dasa.ncsu.edu/"&gt;NCSU Office of Undergraduate Research&lt;/a&gt; to fund his summer research in the lab!&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/our-grant/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/our-grant/</guid> </item> <item><title>American Physical Society March Meeting, Boston, MA</title> <description>&lt;div class="row"&gt;&lt;div class="col-md-6"&gt;&lt;div class="media"&gt; &lt;img width=600 class="media-object" src="/eltinglab/images/news/apsmmTrain.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Last minute talk prep, somewhere between Philadelphia and Boston&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Boston found itself under several inches of snow, Mary traveled for 12 hours in planes, trains, and automobiles to reach the American Physical Society March Meeting. (The travel, or at least the train part, was more fun than it sounds!) While there, she gave a talk on work in the lab from Marc Begley and Elizabeth Davis on &amp;quot;Probing the mechanical organization of k-fiber microtubule bundles within the mammalian mitotic spindle via targeted laser ablation and speckle microscopy.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/apsmm/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/apsmm/</guid> </item> <item><title>Invited seminar at Notre Dame, Aerospace and Mechanical Engineering</title> <description>&lt;div class="row"&gt;&lt;div class="col-md-6"&gt;&lt;div class="media"&gt; &lt;img width=600 class="media-object" src="/eltinglab/images/news/notreDame.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In February, Mary braved the cold and traveled to South Bend, IN to give an &lt;a href="https://ame.nd.edu/seminars/"&gt;invited seminar&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href="https://ame.nd.edu/"&gt;Department of Aerospace and Mechanical Engineering at Notre Dame&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/notre-dame-seminar/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/notre-dame-seminar/</guid> </item> <item><title>Marc and Mohamed give CMB Seminar</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;Marc and Mohamed gave a shared NCSU Physics &lt;a href="https://physics.sciences.ncsu.edu/events/category/cmb-seminar/"&gt;Complex Matter and Biophysics seminar&lt;/a&gt; on their progress on &amp;quot;K-Fiber Dynamical Response to Molecular and Mechanical Perturbations&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Laser Ablation to Probe Furrow Ingression Mechanisms in Schizosaccharomyces Pombe,&amp;quot; respectively. Great job, Marc and Mohamed!&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/cmb-seminar/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/cmb-seminar/</guid> </item> <item><title>Welcome, Shannon Harris</title> <description>&lt;div class="row"&gt;&lt;div class="col-md-6"&gt;&lt;div class="media"&gt; &lt;img width=600 class="media-object" src="/eltinglab/images/team/SH_labPhoto.JPEG"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In December, the Elting Lab hired our sixth lab member, &lt;a href=""/eltinglab/images/team/shannon-harris/"&gt;Shannon Harris&lt;/a&gt;. Shannon is a Masters student in the Biotechnology program at NCSU and will be a half-time technician in our lab. Welcome to Shannon!&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/welcome-shannon/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/welcome-shannon/</guid> </item> <item><title>American Society for Cell Biology Meeting, San Diego, CA</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;Mary traveled to San Diego, CA to the American Society of Cell Biology meeting in December to present Marc and Elizabeth&amp;#39;s work on the mechanics of the mammalian k-fiber, in a poster titled &amp;quot;The mechanical organization of the mammalian k-fiber, probed via targeted laser ablation and speckle microscopy.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/ascb/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/ascb/</guid> </item> <item><title>Triangle Cytoskeleton Meeting</title> <description>&lt;div class="row"&gt;&lt;div class="col-md-6"&gt;&lt;div class="media"&gt; &lt;img width=600 class="media-object" src="/eltinglab/images/team/EltingLabSummer2018.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Elting Lab at the &lt;a href="http://trianglecytoskeleton.com"&gt;Triangle Cytoskeleton Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, Summer 2018&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The entire Elting lab had a great time participating in the Triangle Cytoskeleton Meeting on September 24, 2018. Mary was one of the invited speakers at the &lt;a href="http://trianglecytoskeleton.com/pre-meeting-2018/"&gt;pre-meeting event&lt;/a&gt; on Sunday night. Then on Monday, Ana Sofia and Parsa presented a poster on their work on the mechanics of the &lt;em&gt;S. pombe&lt;/em&gt; mitotic spindle, Mohamed presented his work on ablation of the cytokinetic contractile ring in &lt;em&gt;S. pombe&lt;/em&gt; (a collaboration with &lt;a href="https://laplantelab.wordpress.ncsu.edu/"&gt;Caroline Laplante&lt;/a&gt;), and Marc and Elizabeth presented their work on mammalian k-fiber mechanics. We learned a lot and had a great time at the fantastic venue of the Haw River Ballroom in Saxapahaw, NC!&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/triangle-cytoskeleton-meeting/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/triangle-cytoskeleton-meeting/</guid> </item> <item><title>Two Elting lab undergrads receive PPEP Assistantships!</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Elizabeth Davis and Parsa Zareiesfandabadi on receiving assistanships through the &lt;a href="https://emas.ncsu.edu/employers/professional-experience-program/"&gt;Provost&amp;#39;s Professional Experience Program&lt;/a&gt;! We&amp;#39;re very proud of their proposals and excited about the work that will come from it!&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/ppep-awards/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/ppep-awards/</guid> </item> <item><title>New lab members!</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s been awhile since we&amp;#39;ve updated the blog. Summer is off to a great start with lots of exciting new data - and our lab has grown! We now have five lab members (though Ana Sofia is currently at an REU at the University of Chicago - congrats Ana Sofia!). Check out the &lt;a href="/eltinglab/team"&gt;team page&lt;/a&gt; to hear a little about all our new lab members. &lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/new-members/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/new-members/</guid> </item> <item><title>Mary Receives ORAU Ralph E. Powe Junior Faculty Enhancement Award</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;The Elting lab has its first external funding! Mary is very grateful to the support of the Ralph E. Powe Junior Faculty Enhancement Award from the Oak Ridge Associate Universities (ORAU).&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/powe-award/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/powe-award/</guid> </item> <item><title>Microscope has arrived!</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re so thrilled that our microscope has arrived in the Elting lab! So far it&amp;#39;s just a bunch of crates so we&amp;#39;re anxiously awaiting Monday morning when it will all be installed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;div style="max-width: 600px;"&gt; &lt;img src="/eltinglab/images/news/scopeInBoxes.jpg" alt=""&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hard to believe all of those giant boxes are going to fit on our little optical table! We can&amp;#39;t wait to see it unpacked.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/scope-arrives/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/scope-arrives/</guid> </item> <item><title>Dispatch on Mary's Current Biology paper</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re excited that Helder Maiato and Antonio Pereira wrote a Dispatch for Current Biology on our &lt;a href="/eltinglab/papers/elting-k-fiber-anchorage/"&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; on load-bearing along k-fibers in the mitotic spindle. Check it out &lt;a href="http://www.cell.com/current-biology/abstract/S0960-9822(17)30797-2"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/current-biology-dispatch/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/current-biology-dispatch/</guid> </item> <item><title>Welcome</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome. I&amp;#39;m creating this new Elting Lab website based on the blotter website template created by Trevor Bedford. The original code for that site is available &lt;a href="https://github.com/blab/blotter"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link>http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/welcome/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">http://physics.ncsu.edu/news/welcome/</guid> </item> </channel> </rss>